LEONILO SANTIAGO III

20 Winters Way, Winnipeg, MB, R2G2R2 | 204 293 2473 | leosantiagoiii@outlook.com | https://leosantiagoiii.github.io/

Summary

A detail and solution-oriented IT professional with experience in data management, and web and native applications. I am currently studying Network Infrastructures to further develop my skillset in navigating the ever-changing trends in the field of technology.

Skills & Abilities

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Experience in business software such as SAP MDM, ServiceNow and other company-proprietary applications
- Experience in Software Testing and Data Management
- Background in Network Administration (VoIP, Wireless, and other Networking principles)
- Background in Web Development like front-end designing & backend development (HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap, Adobe Photoshop)
- Proficient use of Microsoft Office
- Knowledgeable in SDLC

TRANSFERRABLE SKILLS

- Willing to explore new things and be trained
- Easily adaptable to business changes and is a fast learner
- Is a team-player, and can step up to the leadership role if need be
- Bilingual (fluent in English and Tagalog)
- Detail-oriented in tasks and responsibilities to avoid errors in the business process
- Equipped with interpersonal skills to easily work with co-workers and clients alike

Experience

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT | DXC TECHNOLOGY • MANILA, PHILIPPINES February 2020 – April 2021

Maintained pricing data integrity for an international manufacturing and marketing company using ERP programs such as ServiceNow and SAP MDM. Had familiarity in the business process to answer queries and fulfill data management requests from clients.

Responsibilities

- Generated daily reports regarding workflow and backlogs
- Generated monthly reports for team productivity and progression
- Monitored pricing data changes within the system and immediately corrected it once it was determined to be an error
- Responsible for data quality checks every day and week to make sure pricing information entered into the system were accurate and precise

- Loaded prices into the system and ensured no errors were present, avoiding data discrepancy
- Created documentation for both new and outdated processes for audit purposes
- Led the pricing team for the quarterly pricing resync

SOFTWARE QUALITY ASSURANCE INTERN | DELTEK SYSTEMS • MANILA, PHILIPPINES June 2019 – September 2019

Ensured the company's software application were free from any errors and bugs before the specified product launch, and this was done by using proprietary QA testing program.

Responsibilities

- The creation of Object Mapping scripts for CRUD (Create, Read, Update and Delete) Testing and documenting any bugs encountered
- Step-by-step recreation of bugs
- Verifying recreated bugs
- Participated in Peer Testing where I ran the team's test scripts to confirm if the process was done correctly

Academic Background

NETWORK SERVICES TECHNICIAN | RED RIVER COLLEGE POLYTECHNIC • WINNIPEG, MB August 2021 - Present

- Exploring network administration in a SOHO-level environment that involves basic device configurations for switches, routers, servers, and host devices such as desktop computers, laptops, network printers, etc. using physical equipment and the Packet Tracer software.
- Equipped with troubleshooting skills and ensures stability and Quality of Service for all devices within the network to maintain and improve network services.
- Studied cable designing for buildings and homes using Microsoft Visio
- Fall 2021 GPA of 4.50, and is expected to graduate in April 2022

Related coursework: Network Infrastructures, Windows OS, Linux OS, VoIP, Network Security, Structured Cabling

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | DE LA SALLE LIPA • LIPA, PHILIPPINES August 2016 – July 2019

- Learned theoretical and practical concepts in the field of computing science and heavily focused on how to improve business processes using software.
- Had introduction in project management incorporating SDLC with the thesis presented.
- Cumulative GPA of 1.75 (equivalent to 89-91%)

Related coursework: Web Development, Feasibility Studies, Network Principles, Information Management, Human-Computer Interaction, Algorithms, SDLC

Activities & Recognitions

CERTIFICATES ACQUIRED

- NDG Linux 1 Completion Certificate 17 Dec 2021
- General Safety Training (GST) Completion Certificate 29 Aug 2021
- Workplace Hazardous Materials Information System (WHMIS) Completion Certificate 25 Aug 2021

BRITISH COUNCIL

• Recognized as of the IELTS Champs for attaining a band of 8.0 out of 9.0 in the IELTS Assessment, an international standardized for non-native English speakers.

DELTEK SYSTEMS

• Received awards namely: Defect Chaser Award, Perfect Attendance, Internship Excellence Award

DE LA SALLE LIPA

- Dean's List Award for 4 consecutive semesters (S.Y. 2017-2019)
- Vice President for an in-campus organization, ALI (Alliance of Lasallian Innovators)

INDUSTRY VISIT

• Had the opportunity to visit numerous companies in the IT industry and learned about the current tech and business trends (Nokia, Cisco, DXC Technology, etc.)

PROJECTS

- Submitted a thesis project for college that helped a local business and implemented a reservation system for them.
- Designed the UI for my hometown's college website
- Created my personal website

VOLUNTEERING

• Helped the church distribute relief goods to people affected by the Taal Volcano eruption in 2020

Character References

Available upon request